<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Srijan R. Shetty</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="//srijanshetty.in/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in" />
<updated>2025-06-08T10:47:19+05:30</updated>
<id>//srijanshetty.in/</id>
<author>
  <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
  <uri>//srijanshetty.in/</uri>
  <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Starting allround]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/startups/on-starting-allround/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/startups/on-starting-allround</id>
  <published>2025-06-01T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2025-06-01T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://allroundclub.com&quot;&gt;allround&lt;/a&gt;, the first startup that I attempted was a calculated decision.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I loved my job at Goldman Sachs, and was working with one of the best teams in low latency algorithms and brilliant people. My only qualm was a career trajectory which was a conventional growth path and it wasn’t fast enough for me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m a big believer of taking the path not taken where the expected value of success is far higher due to reduced competition. Or, compete in tail ends of the gaussian curve and find unorthodox ways to win.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why? If your objective is fame/money/power/success/ambition, it’s far better to not compete at all. And after having competed in JEE, I did not look forward to rising up ranks through conventional competition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I will acknowledge my privilege here, a CS degree from IITK gives you some latitude of freedom to explore if you’re actually good at tech. Combining this with an acquired extroversion made a potent combination, which I believed would allow me to fulfil the Indian Tech Bro’s dreaming of raising funds to build something of their own (sic).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the whirlwind of the pandemic, allround was born and buried. Amidst the perfect storm, we saw the varied highs and lows of building a startup. Raising funds, scaling, hockeystick growth, churn, international expansion, pivots, lay offs, vagaries of the consumer and market, firing close friends, laying off a huge chunk of the team (and finding them jobs), and eventually closing down the company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
allround remains a labour of love, and the experience taught me a lot about life, friends and hard work. 
At the end of it all, I wasn’t even sure that I wanted to get my hands dirty starting up again and that’s why I spent most of 2022 blowing steam after a burn out and having fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fuze was built with a different mindset and we’ll come to that very soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/startups/on-starting-allround/&quot;&gt;On Starting allround&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on June 01, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor TVP]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-tvp-2/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-tvp-2</id>
  <published>2025-02-10T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2025-02-10T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Professors has completely autonomy over their courses at Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur, and boy o boy, did it translate to some really fun and innovating grading schemes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Professor TV Prabhakar (or Professor TVP) is probably of the coolest professor that I can recall from my days of college. I’ve already written about the time when he cancelled a class on account of it being April’s fool and gave us a chai party instead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But this is the story of the first time we met him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Traditionally, the first class of any course at IIT Kanpur is an overview of the course to set expectations. The professor will talk about how they intend to structure the credits of the course, the niti-grities of grading, lecture splits, workshops, practical and theory. Incidentally this is also the class with probably the most attendance as the ‘ethu’ is high during the start of the semester and wanes with students getting back into the rhythm of college life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of professors over the course have had interesting takes on the grading system and I’ve countless stories to share from open book exams, to semi-infinite time boxed exams (this was an interesting one), but Professor TVP threw what can be called as a ‘googly’.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Grading is an exercise in game theory. Most professors want to optimize for classes attended, effort or maybe even learning, but Professor TVP had wilder plans.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And hence on the very first day of class - just like Morpheus in Matrix did - presented all the students with a
choice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You could chose the blue pill - where you continue with the course as usual - tests, mid-terms, end-iterms, classes et al.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Or you could choose the red pill - don’t attend any single class and instead build out an interesting project on which you will be graded. A project which could eventually stand on it’s own legs like any good startup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A few students did choose the latter, but for the rest of us not only did he make us take tests, mid-terms, end-terms. But also he got us to do a project at a smaller scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Talk about having the cake and eating the cherry too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-tvp-2/&quot;&gt;The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor TVP&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on February 10, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor Dheeraj Sanghi]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-dheeraj-sanghi/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-dheeraj-sanghi</id>
  <published>2025-02-03T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2025-02-03T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The one thing that Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur taught me was that you can just do things.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the story of professor Dheeraj Sanghi, probably one of the most based professors of IITK because he didn’t care for the status quo on most instances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mozilla had launched their ‘Winter of Security’ Programme to compete with Google’s Summer of Code. But they had one catch, it was supposed to be during the semester.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now, in any normal institute, this would be categorized as ‘extra-curricular’ work - after all what is the application of security principles in a college that is known for solving some of the most pressing matters of theoretical computer science. And which college would allow you to get grades for ‘Open Source Contributions’ in Network Security?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But, then IIT Kanpur isn’t a normal college.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And to top it all off, Professor Dheeraj Sanghi had done something never done before, he constructed a class on ‘Network Security’ as a series of lectures by the best minds of ‘Security’ in the country. Here was a professor inviting industry professionals to teach a subject to kids and who himself was open to learn more about a rapidly evolving space.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I assembled two more crazy batchmates and thought maybe we should knock on the doors of our favorite renegade Professor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Professor Dheeraj Sanghi - who was also running the show as the DOAA - was a busy man and he could have easily shunned us away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Instead, he entertained the wild ideas of three kids who wanted to overload him with a UGP which would be spent contributing to Open Source and wherein he would be required to spend significant resources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At this point, we were happy in just getting an audience to our idea. And a reasonable person would have said no but then what is reason to ambition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not only did Professor Dheeraj Sanghi agree to our wild plan. He spent the entire semster helping us because in the end we were one of the only teams to have been accepted for ‘Mozilla Winter of Security’ in India and were one of 12 teams across the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I learned a valuable lesson - You can just do things, and people will go out of their way to support you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-dheeraj-sanghi/&quot;&gt;The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor Dheeraj Sanghi&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on February 03, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Probability and Statistics]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-attendance/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-attendance</id>
  <published>2025-01-07T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2025-01-07T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;While it’s well know that BITS Pilani has no mandatory attendance, not a lot of folks know that Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur also doesn’t mandate attendance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the story of the only course I never attended in my four years of IIT Kanpur and how the professor tried to bribe the students to attend classes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The most dreaded class that you could sign up for is the 8am class in the winters.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Winter temperatures in IIT Kanpur range in 1-5 degrees - a fact that we realized post-hoc due to the lack of curiosity and modern day smart phones. But what was nerve wracking is that you had no recourse to heaters.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And if you’re wondering why we did not have recourse to heaters? Well, because the hostel most seniors get are ‘old’ as they have more ‘legacy’. And with great legacy comes prehistoric wiring which cannot withstand the power demand of more than 10 heaters. In a classic tragedy of commons, if more than 10 people use heaters, the entire hostel’s electricity would blow out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We battled the cold, the old fashioned way. 4 blankets, 3 trousers, 3 socks, a monkey cap.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So, getting students to wake up at 8am is a professor’s worst nightmare. Now couple that with a class of 500 students on Probability.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The session in January started with the usual enthusiasm with a turnout of over 100%. You would expect that everyone would get a hand of probability because you read that in JEE. But by week 3 most students were either lost or were not attending the classes. Attendance fell by atleast 50% (or so I think because I was one of those who did not dare leave his bed). Just a few weeks before mid-term, a pittance of 20 students were attending classes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Most professors would not bat an eyelid, after all, a professors primary job is not teaching.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But every once in a while professors want to have some fun. So one fine day in February he decided to mandate 10% of marks for attendance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For those of you who haven’t attended classes with relative grading. 10% is the difference between an ‘A’ grade and a ‘C’ grade, or in some cases the line between flunking a course and comfortably passing one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And the ‘cherry on top’? It was a random roll-call, which essentially was a class on probability in a class on probability. With 500 students and 40 classes left you can do the math about what your probability for being roll called on a particular day can be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This had the intended effect, the classes were packed post the mid-sems.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m sure you’re wondering what happened to me? Didn’t I mention that I did not attend any of the classes for this particular course? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Well, I only spoke a half-truth. Yes, I did not attend any class till the very last day because not only did I hate the cold more than the upside of 10% marks, but because my name was never called. Which meant that I rushed on the final day just before the final class to get my name marked and managed to those precious 10% marks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Despite those 10% marks, this was my Scarlett letter in my gradesheet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-attendance/&quot;&gt;The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Probability and Statistics&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on January 07, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A curious case of 520 errors with Nodejs and ALB]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/520-errors-with-Nodejs-and-ALB/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/520-errors-with-Nodejs-and-ALB</id>
  <published>2024-11-10T10:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2024-11-10T10:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to get your hands dirty and go down the rabbit hole.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was exactly what we had to do when we saw intermittent 502 errors on our API stack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/502_errors.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;502 errors on AWS ALB&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial hypothesis was restarts at night, but the frequency of the errors was higher than the number of automated restarts. So to dig deeper we accessed the access logs of ALB (which are stored in gzip and add a minor inconvenience).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The logs were inconclusive or I was unable to make sense of the access logs, so it was time for some old fashioned googling. After going through dead end after dead ends, we came across an &lt;a href=&quot;https://repost.aws/knowledge-center/elb-alb-troubleshoot-502-errors&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, two things stood out for me on the article:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If the &lt;strong&gt;elb_status_code&lt;/strong&gt; is “502” and the &lt;strong&gt;target_status_code&lt;/strong&gt; is “-“, then your load balancer is the source of the HTTP 502 errors. If the &lt;strong&gt;elb_status_code&lt;/strong&gt; is “502” and the &lt;strong&gt;target_status_code&lt;/strong&gt; is “502”, then your target is the source of the errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The target receives the request and starts to process it, but closes the connection to the load balancer too early. This usually occurs when the duration of the keep-alive timeout for the target is shorter than the idle timeout value of the load balancer. Make sure that the duration of the keep-alive timeout is greater than the idle timeout value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Check the values for the request_processing_time, target_processing_time and response_processing_time fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this knowledge the most likely culprit was express on nodejs having a shorter timeout than ALB On checking it was clear that express had a timeout of 5s which ALB had 60s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On updating ALB keepalives to 4s, the errors no longer appeared.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was a fun little problem that we chanced upon while setting up our API infrastructure which had us going into the weeds of Nodejs, express and ALB.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/520-errors-with-Nodejs-and-ALB/&quot;&gt;A curious case of 520 errors with Nodejs and ALB&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on November 10, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/travel/japan/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/travel/japan</id>
  <published>2024-11-09T10:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2024-11-09T10:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve always been immersed in Japanese culture. Dragon Ball Z, Pokemon, Beyblade, Death Note, Code Geass, Naruto, &lt;em&gt;Kimi no Na wa&lt;/em&gt;, Murakami.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But even that could not have prepared me for the whirlwind that Japan is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Movies, anime and books capture only a sliver of the Japanese experience. The sensory overload of being in the streets of Shinjuku or Shibuyu, listening to the cacophony of the eclectic crowd crossing the crowded streets, under lucid neon lights and drenched in the myriads flavours emanating from the streets is hard to convey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Japan is everything you hope it to be and more; it’s one of the few places you experience a real culture shock because it is unlike any other place in the planet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My greatest takeaway of Japan and the reason I’ll keep revisiting has to be the food. I’ve had probably 20-30 full meals and countless knick-knacks in the time I spent in Japan, and all of those meals would probably feature in the top 100 meals I’ve every had in my life. From delicious ramen in a ramshackle store, to a Michelin star omakase experience with 12 courses - we had them all and all of them were equally delicious (apart from every Instagram recommendation and even they were great). The variety of cuisines that you can try is dumfounding - sushi, sashimi, teppanyaki, kaiseki, ramen, udon noodles, yakitori, yakiniki, cup noodles to just name a few of the things we tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You have to book popular places places way ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the places don’t seat more than 20 people at a time, so the ones offering Omakase require reservation. We got lucky by walking into some of the famous places because we were relatively in the off peak season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tabelog is much better than Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a consequence of ratings inflation. The bar of food is very high in Japan and any place you enter would have
great food, which makes Google Maps reviews useless because they are always 4+. Hopefully the Gods of Tablecheck show mercy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Knowing a few Japanese phrases goes a long distance. Google Translate is your friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a method to the madness while travelling in Japan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Their transport system is by far the most advanced I’ve ever seen in any part of the world. For example, we were able to travel from our hotel in Kyoto to our hotel in Osaka in under 43 minutes by using metros and express trains, and we didn’t have to walk more than 5m on either side.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But being the most advanced transport system comes with the challenges of navigating the maze. I hope you never get caught at Shinjuku station at midnight trying to figure out the last train to your hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Again, Google Maps is your friend here. And if you’ve never used Google Maps to navigate directions of metros, exits of underground systems, now would be a good time to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;money&quot;&gt;Money&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;get by without cash&lt;/strong&gt;, but then you would be getting by without the quintessential experience of Japan - street food, fun and random frolic. So I would highly advise against it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
ATMS are a plenty if you’re like me who doesn’t like to carry more than required cash.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The number of payment methods in Japan on most restaurants is mind boggling. Chances are your card - credit/debit/forex/charge/prepaid will work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But the holy grail of money is the &lt;strong&gt;TRAVEL CARD&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Suica&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s a prepaid travel card which works on metros/trains/buses/restaurants/stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You should add SUICA to your Apple Wallet. The express travel card works even if your phone battery is dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to change the Media Location on your phone to US (don’t change apple store location, change the media location - &lt;a href=&quot;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/254449023&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;. Once done, you can goto Add Card -&amp;gt; Add Travel Card -&amp;gt; Suica. I had a credit card in Apple Wallet which made life so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;culture&quot;&gt;Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the beginning, &lt;strong&gt;the culture shock of Japan is real&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The streets have all kinds of eclectic people - from salary men and women in suits and ties to kids donning the whackiest street wear clothes possible. The trains will have folks returning from work in a work attire to folks in casual cosplay clothes or gothic appearances and no one batting an eye-lid.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Lawsons and Family Marts - the convenience stores are a treasure trove. They are stocked with delicious take away food, juices that you can prepare at the store, cup-noodles with hot water dispensers for you to eat; and all kinds of potent alcohol with people consuming food and alcohol right outside the stores.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can spend hours people watching at Shinjuku, Harijuku, Dotonburi in Osaka.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Vending machines abound the streets in the most unlikeliest of places and serving the most bizarre things possible - orange juice, water, CDs, pokemon cards to name a few.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, strangely there are no trash cans anywhere. You carry your own trash and dispose it off at your work or your hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The beauty of Japan is that you can experience Zen at a Shinto shrine in Mt. Fuji to the anxiety of traversing Shinjuku station in the same trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can revel at the peace of shrines which are centuries old or marvel at mega structures of the modern metropolises and transport systems that work like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And this is also probably the reason that a single trip to Japan can hardly capture what this country has to
offer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And this also probably the reason I’ve already planned my next visit there.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/travel/japan/&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on November 09, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The missing guide to TailScale subnet routing in AWS]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/tailscale-subnet-router/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/tailscale-subnet-router</id>
  <published>2024-09-24T10:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2024-09-24T10:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of TailScale, and we extensively use it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuze.finance&quot;&gt;Fuze&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While most of the guides of TailScale are straightforward, I’ve found the section on subnet routers a bit obtuse or incomplete for the lack of a better word.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So here’s my guide on how to setup a subnet router which will allow you to access private IPs on an AWS subnet (or any subnet) directly from TailScale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You need to setup a jumpbox, this box has tailscale installed. Let’s give it a SG called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tailscale-subnet-router&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that the jumpbox has the ‘Source and Destination’ checks disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-jsx highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;In&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Instances&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;panel&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;find&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;instance&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;just&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;created&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Choose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Actions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Change&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;destination&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;check&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;For&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;destination&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;checking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Stop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Choose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Save&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that hosts you want to connect to have a SG which accepts &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Inbound Connections&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tailscale-subnet-router&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now we add the configuration in our TailScale ACL policy, to allow a group &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devops&lt;/code&gt; to access it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;ipsets&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;ipset:subnet&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;111.10.0.0/16&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;grants&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;src&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;group:devops&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;dst&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ipset:subnet&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;   
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a final step, we need to allow our current host accept routes published by the subnet router&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tailscale up &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--accept-routes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These steps should do the trick and you should be able to connect to subnet from your local machine now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tailscale.com/kb/1019/subnets&quot;&gt;Tailscale Subnet Router&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tailscale.com/kb/1021/install-aws#technical-requirements&quot;&gt;Tailscale Subnet Router Technical Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/tailscale-subnet-router/&quot;&gt;The missing guide to TailScale subnet routing in AWS&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 24, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heath Checks on a Custom Port for Websockets with ALB]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/custom-port-websockets-alb/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/custom-port-websockets-alb</id>
  <published>2024-04-09T19:53:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2024-04-09T19:53:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This blog has been written because there wasn’t any good comprehensive guide to run a websocket server using AWS Load Balancer where the health check runs on a different port.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In theory (and practice) you can run health checks on the same port as your web socket server, but unfortunately ALB does not support native WS communications. In fact all communications are using HTTP 1.1 with your Origin Server.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The websocket server at Fuze is a single binary which runs an express server for health checks. (There is an argument to be made that it isn’t a true health check but we digress).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This setup worked well for bare metal EC2 instances which we use in development, but our production servers which use ECS didn’t play along. We had two choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change the code to run the health check on the same port as the web socket server. Which would be complicated as we would have to handle two different protocols on the same port and would require code changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out if ALB can be persuaded to perform health checks on a different port. Which from a cursory check felt not possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose the former because &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Programmer Time is Expensive&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As mentioned above, most guides explicitly mentioned that this isn’t possible. But while experimenting, we found an escape hatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-ws-stackexchange-question.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Stack Exchange isn't of much help in this case&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, the first step in attaching an origin server to ALB requires setting up &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Target Group&lt;/code&gt; with the port of the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-aws-target-group.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Setting up a target group in AWS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next step, where we setup the Health Check, we saw an undocumented feature of overriding the Health Check Port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-aws-health-check.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Override the health check port to the port of the express server&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And viola, we’re all done.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/custom-port-websockets-alb/&quot;&gt;Heath Checks on a Custom Port for Websockets with ALB&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on April 09, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up AWS Peering Connections for Wazuh and ECS]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/aws-peering-connections/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/aws-peering-connections</id>
  <published>2024-02-10T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2024-02-10T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;As I’ve written before Fuze is a security company as much as it is a finance and technology company. In addition to having a strong testing culture at Fuze, we also have a strong security culture by including security in the SLDC supply chain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/aws_ecs.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;AWS ECS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Fuze, we used AWS ECS to deploy our production infrastructure and CI/CD is run through GitHub Actions. The only difference between our development and production infrastructure is that for simplicity we run development on EC2 with TailScale to enforce strong ACL. No one has access to production without a break glass procedure. (We have two separate accounts for production and development to enforece strict security)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/wazuh.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Wazuh&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another core pillar of our infrastructure is self host as much as possible. We recently started using Wazuh as our open source SIEM, but it wasn’t without challenges. Because Wazuh is hosted in a different VPC than our production hosts, they cannot communicate directly. With our development infrastructure this is easily mitigated by using TailScale connections but we have ensured that production is completely isolated for now. The easy solution is to run TailScale and get done with it, but for some reason Tailscale breaks code deploys to ECS with GitHub actions. (This is something that I intend to explore in the coming few months but after extensive tests, we were able to establish that the root cause is TailScale).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One option would have been to use agent less monitoring on Wazuh but we did not want to use SSH private keys or passwords for connections because they are inherently security unless combined with key rotation and we prefer not to dabble with key rotation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In light of the above, and after a week or two of head scratching, I was finally able to come up with a solution of this conundrum - AWS Peering Connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/vpc_peering.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;AWS VPC Perring connections&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to setup a peering connection from the prod vpc to the wazuh vpc. This looked straightforward in theory but didn’t work because every documentation missed one vital step. Adding routing tables which missing in both the documentation of Wazuh and peering connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/route_tables.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;AWS VPC route tables&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After setting up the route table, our Wazuh server was successfully able to connect with the production instances and vice versa. This enabled the instances to send all telemetry and information about any security event that happened on the hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/aws-peering-connections/&quot;&gt;Setting up AWS Peering Connections for Wazuh and ECS&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on February 10, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unit Testing Typescript in under 10 seconds]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/unit-test/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/unit-test</id>
  <published>2023-09-01T10:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I test in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing any programmer wants to do is write tests. And I get it, I’ve been there. Writing tests can be boring. And I’m not going to give you a long lecture about why you should write tests, I’m just going to show what we’ve done at Fuze over the course of the next 2-3 posts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This particular post is about the fundamental unit of testing - Unit Testing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To lay the foundation, our goal is to have greater than 99% test coverage for statements, branches, function and
lines.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The headline numbers at Fuze for Unit Testing right now are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Functions, Lines - 100%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statements - 99.4%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Branches - 99.51%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for a non-trivial codebase of 120k LOC and over 1200 tests.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The big question is not why, it’s how and the answer at Fuze has been twofold:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Firstly, we have a complex system that has many moving parts, so everyone realizes the importance of testing and we’ve built a top-down ‘testing’ culture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Secondly, we make testing fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our tests run under the target goal of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;15s&lt;/code&gt;, and at more than 1200 test cases, this is possible because we use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;swc&lt;/code&gt; which uses &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/code&gt; to speed up the tests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We heavily rely on automations - GitHub Actions to run the tests. While we could have configured pre-commit hooks to run them we decided against it because it slows down development cycles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new few posts I’ll talk about API testing, Integration tests, Stress Testing and Vulnerability
management.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Do let me know if you liked the above post in the comments below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/unit-test/&quot;&gt;Unit Testing Typescript in under 10 seconds&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 01, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[OARS, SQL Injections and Paper Backups]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/oars-sql-injections-and-paper-backups/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/oars-sql-injections-and-paper-backups</id>
  <published>2023-08-01T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2023-08-01T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;OARS - Four letters that could fill any graduate of IIT Kanpur from 2009 to 2015 with abject horror.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While presented as a system to register for courses for the next semester, it was a machine of widespread torture by crushing your hopes and your soul at the exact moment that they are the highest. The beauty of OARS was that it was universally hated by both students and professors, a common themes across most of IIT Kanpur.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
An apocryphal story states that OARS was cobbled together by a few undergraduates over a summer, and things turned for the worst when it gained sentience. Probably some reader might shed light on the real origin story of OARS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This story is not about the origins of OARs though, it’s about how a close friend found out an SQL injection attack that gave them root access to OARS - I would have loved to take credit, but alas that would be a lie. The said friend had access to the academic records of every student on the campus, and since they were honour bound they never did anything more with it (or did they?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Dean of Academic Affairs knew about the shortcomings of OARS - he was also the professor who eventually slayed the demon of OARS to another demon, which I’ve heard doesn’t give students cold sweats a day before registrations. When we approached him with the potential vulnerability, he responded with absolutely no change in expression - “That means that what I’ve been teaching in computer security has been useful to you lot. Also, having access doesn’t really make much difference, we have paper records and emails are triggered on every change. You’re bound by the honour code, so the best you can do is swoop around but that you could do anyways if you are ‘smart’ enough.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We were dumbfounded, for not only did he sign us to a honour contract at the spot, but also told us that we could have a field day because there were other Easter Eggs on the network. It was akin to giving kids unrestricted access to the candy shop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was a defining moment because you have to admit that sometimes plain old paper records are a secure format and all our fancy dandy security might fall short. A professor bound us by an imaginary honor contract, and three all we did was use our access to build an API so that students could search OARS in a better manner and get to know the top 10 students in each year.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/oars-sql-injections-and-paper-backups/&quot;&gt;OARS, SQL Injections and Paper Backups&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on August 01, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor TVP]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-professor-tvp/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-professor-tvp</id>
  <published>2023-05-01T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2023-05-01T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Professors in Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur are based and here is another story of such a professor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
IIT Kanpur provides complete autonomy to professors, they can run the classes according to their whims and
fancies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The reason we don’t have mandatory attendance is the professors only want interested students, and yet some classes are jam packed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One such professor was Professor TVP. If you imagine professors being grumpy old men with pot bellies, you’ll be wrong more often than not in college.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Professor TVP sported grey hair, but that’s the only indication of him being aged as his energy in the class was infectious.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s was April 1st and while everyone was in the class, no one really wanted to study that day. The day was nice and sunny, and considering it was “April’s Fool’s”, the devil is bound to have some fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As soon as the professor entered and and before he could utter a single word, a student stood up deadpan and
said:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“It’s Aprils Fool’s day today and we should not study.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A normal professor would shut down such a student - but not Professor TVP. In his zest he said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“I absolutely agree.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Silence. The students were in shock and awe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“The day is nice and sunny, let’s go grab some chai in CC canteen. Treat’s on me.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And so all 40 students, walked to and gheroed CC canteen grabbing some chai amongst some ridiculously nosy peacocks (story for another time).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Told you, never underestimate the Professors of IIT Kanpur. They can surprise you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-professor-tvp/&quot;&gt;The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor TVP&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on May 01, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor Biswas]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-professor-biswas/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-professor-biswas</id>
  <published>2023-03-01T20:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2023-03-01T20:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This wasn’t because we had diligent students who attended all classes, on the contrary Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur didn’t have a mandatory attendance policy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And yet, the rumour mill didn’t churn with the news of a ‘mass bunk’, until CSE Y11 did.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It was the last class before spring break of 2013 and Professor Biswas was teaching us ‘Abstract Algebra’ (side note, it’s still abstract for me). Ten minutes before the class, a student decides to pull off a legendary coup - he just needs to convince 10 students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first seven students are easy to convince, it’s the last three - the most studious of the lot which take the most time. But he prevails and convinces an entire class to ‘mass bunk’.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What happens in the following days is something unique - silence. No angry emails by the professor, no students asked to visit the professor’s cabin. There isn’t even a minor mention in the corridors of the Motwani building.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Post spring-break as we enter Professor Biswas’s class, there is an air of mystery.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Professor Biswas enters the class in his usual style - a grey mane with Rayban aviators, all he needed was a leather jacket to be in an American movie about a renegade teacher. In a very anti-climactic fashion, he pounces straight to the board and starts teaching Chapter 14.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is when a general dread kicks in across the classroom - we were on Chapter 9. When a brave students points out this discrepancy to the professor, he casually mentions:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“I finished chapters 9 to 14 in the previous class”.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“Also, I conducted a quiz. Students can collect their answer sheets from my cabin later in the day”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s time for the students to remain silent. Shell shocked, Professor Biswas had the last laugh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We learnt a valuable lesson, you don’t mess with professors, especially the professors at IIT Kanpur.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/write-ups/based-professors-of-iitk-professor-biswas/&quot;&gt;The based professors of IIT Kanpur - Professor Biswas&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[On missing the shared intimacy of friendships]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/prose/shared-experiences/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/prose/shared-experiences</id>
  <published>2022-11-22T00:04:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-11-22T00:04:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;What really hurts is not the loss of friendship, but the loss of intimacy. The ability to walk into your best friend’s room at a moment’s notice, the roar of laughter in the room next door when you return from your classes. The spontaneous eruption of joy and tears over a few drinks you smuggled into the hostel from the prying eyes of the guards.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As you grow older and friendships yonder, you miss not a time long lost, you miss the shared experience of it all. Our digital existence can never fill the void of shared experiences, and in our pursuit of ambition we often let these experiences slide. Human presence is abstract and in our hapless hope that the lack of thereof can still power friendships, we carry on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s not adulting, it’s the human condition. We consistently seek strifes as we believe that it’s the struggles that give our existence meaning, and when the hangman comes knocking he’ll smile over our futility in giving up something valuable in pursuit of something that never existed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Srijan R Shetty&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/prose/shared-experiences/&quot;&gt;On missing the shared intimacy of friendships&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on November 22, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving 4 TB across cloud storage providers for free]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/hacks/rclone-moving-files/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/hacks/rclone-moving-files</id>
  <published>2022-09-29T00:41:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-09-29T00:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Ever run into the problem of maxing out your cloud capacity in one provider (most possibly on the free tier) and being
left with no other solution but to upgrade because you can’t move your data?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Or got into the solution of migrating data from a work account to a backup?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I got into somewhat of a fix lately as I had to transfer over 4TB of data from AWS to a Google Drive account (with
infinite free storage, courtesty my alma mater). What makes matters worse is that I have only 4TB of metered usuage in
my broadband network, post which I’m downgraded on speed (and we obviously don’t like slow networks).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The final solution that I came up with didn’t drain by broadband quota and didn’t cost me in time or money, which I
think is a great outcome.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The trick is to run the transfer on a VPS solution like &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalocean.com&quot;&gt;digitalocean&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; to resume
sessions. This allows you to use the bandwidth of the VPS providers and not your home network!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Let’s get everything setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a free digital ocean account using this &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.do.co/c/c7d0b328194e&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spin up a basic Ubuntu instance on Digital Ocean.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://rclone.org/install/&quot;&gt;rclone&lt;/a&gt; using the following command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-v&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; curl https://rclone.org/install.sh | &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rclone&lt;/code&gt; is the swiss army knife of transferring files between different service providers, unlike &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; it does allow
you to transfer between two different hosts and doesn’t have a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;one local node&lt;/code&gt; policy. With rclone setup, the rest is
easy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Install the cloud providers that you want to transfer files between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rclone config

Name                 Type
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;====&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;====&lt;/span&gt;
dropbox              dropbox
s3                   s3

e&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Edit existing remote
n&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; New remote
d&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Delete remote
r&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Rename remote
c&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Copy remote
s&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Set configuration password
q&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Quit config
e/n/d/r/c/s/q&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the source and destination providers setup, the transfer is easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rclone copy s3:bucket.name/ dropbox:backup/ &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--ignore-existing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--ignore-existing&lt;/code&gt; makes the process idempotent in case the SSH connection fails. I prefer running the
command in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; session so that I can reattach the session in a few days when the transfer might have
completed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Until the next post!&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/hacks/rclone-moving-files/&quot;&gt;Moving 4 TB across cloud storage providers for free&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 29, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Handling CORS with cloudflare workers]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/cloudflare-workers-cors/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/cloudflare-workers-cors</id>
  <published>2022-09-26T00:41:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-09-26T00:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve been experimenting with various &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;new age&lt;/code&gt; deployment and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;JAMStack&lt;/code&gt; solutions out there.
Since I’ve been using cloudflare for over 8 years (as of writing this post), I thought I’ll give it a shot as a cheap
caching server replacing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Redis + Node.js&lt;/code&gt;. Writing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/code&gt; server to handle requests using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cloudflare Workers&lt;/code&gt;
and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;KV&lt;/code&gt; is fairly straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;method&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;respondWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;respondWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;postRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;constructResponse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;content-type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;application/json;charset=UTF-8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Handle get requests&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;searchParams&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Some logic to generate data&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;constructResponse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Handle post requests&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;postRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Some logic to generate data&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;constructResponse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as expected, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;httpie&lt;/code&gt; was able to perfectly &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; the data. But as soon as I shot up the devconsole to
make a request, I was faced with the dreaded &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CORS&lt;/code&gt; error. Usually solving CORS is fairly straightforward, but this
error was unique as the request wasn’t really throwing any CORS error, it was just returning an empty
response.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The way to solve this problem is twofold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a handler for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;OPTIONS&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&lt;/code&gt;, on all requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;constructResponse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;content-type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;application/json;charset=UTF-8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;Origin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Handle option requests&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;optionRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;content-type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;application/json;charset=UTF-8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;Origin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;GET, HEAD, POST, OPTIONS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t think I was able to find a solution on the internet, but knowing how &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CORS&lt;/code&gt; is handled helped.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/cloudflare-workers-cors/&quot;&gt;Handling CORS with cloudflare workers&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 26, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZSH bindkey in MacOSX for Cmd]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/hacks/macos-alt-dot-bindkey/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/hacks/macos-alt-dot-bindkey</id>
  <published>2022-09-21T00:41:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-09-21T00:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Another short one but very useful trick in my moving from Linux to Mac series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One of my most used shortcuts in the terminal is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Alt + .&lt;/code&gt;, which I adapted from my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt; workflow to my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; workflow
when I started using zsh. It basically inserts the last word from the previous command. This turns out to be very handy
and I use it multiple times a day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There is no out of the box way to accomplish this on Mac, unless you use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iTerm&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first step is opening up iTerm preferences and navigate to the keybindings section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/mac_zsh_keybinding_1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mac_zsh_keybinding_1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;iTerm &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Keybindings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once in the keybindings section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the dialogue select any Keyboard Shortcut you want. I used &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cmd + .&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Action&lt;/code&gt; as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Send Escape Sequence&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;altdot&lt;/code&gt; as the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Escape Sequence&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Save&lt;/code&gt; and we’re done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/mac_zsh_keybinding_2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mac_zsh_keybinding_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Add Keyboard Shorcut with Send Escape Sequence&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is configuring zsh keybindings to process the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Escape sequence&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-zsh&quot; data-lang=&quot;zsh&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# somewhere in your zsh config&lt;/span&gt;
bindkey &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;^[altdot&quot;&lt;/span&gt; insert-last-word&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And viola, now the keybindings work. This process works &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mutatis mundis&lt;/code&gt; for other keybindings that you want to import
from your workflow in bash/zsh from linux.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/hacks/macos-alt-dot-bindkey/&quot;&gt;ZSH bindkey in MacOSX for Cmd&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 21, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using TouchId for sudo in Mac OSX]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/hacks/sudo-touch-id/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/hacks/sudo-touch-id</id>
  <published>2022-09-14T00:41:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-09-14T00:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This one is short, I wanted to use TouchId for sudo in Mac OSX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Edit pam.d&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;vi /etc/pam.d/sudo

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Add the following as the first line&lt;/span&gt;
auth sufficient pam_tid.so&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Works like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/hacks/sudo-touch-id/&quot;&gt;Using TouchId for sudo in Mac OSX&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 14, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polygon Devfolio Fellowship]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/polygon-devfolio-fellowship/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/polygon-devfolio-fellowship</id>
  <published>2022-09-12T18:32:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-09-12T18:32:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Hi, “I’m the other Srijan, the one not from Devfolio” was the byline I’ve been forced to use for the past two months as
a certain &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/srijancse&quot;&gt;srijan&lt;/a&gt; has monopolized the byline. Yes, it was ardous but at the same time it
was incredibly fun and that line is probably a concise description of everything I was upto at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xPolygon&quot;&gt;0xPolygon&lt;/a&gt; x &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devfolio&quot;&gt;devfolio&lt;/a&gt; Fellowship.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ll be honest, it wasn’t easy being the amongst the oldest of the lot in a hackerhouse and I’d be lying if I said that
my age represented the age old wisdom of experience. The fellowship was replete with build00rs of all ages, and every
minute was spent learning about the amazing ideas that the fellows were working on - from DeFi yield farming to the
beauties of Account Abstraction, and ingeniuty of MeV searchers. The countless hours discussing the frontier of web3 and
hacking along with the best of the build00rs of ecosystem is time that I shall definitely cherish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My idea for the fellowship was to try and solve the problem of decentralized hiring through
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bytrinity.xyz&quot;&gt;Trinity&lt;/a&gt;. Hiring is a broken process and it leaves no one happy. Potential candidates are
optimizing for Data Structures and Algorithms (DSA), while employers are unable to come up with a comprehensive solution
to test the technical skills of the candidates without any Proof Of Work (PoW). Trinity tries to solve this problem
using a novel approach of adding a layer of validators who conduct technical interviews of the candidates and provide
them with skill NFTs (now and Soul Bound Tokens) later to solve the cold-start problem of hiring. If a candidate gets
hired, the validators earn a small comission from the employer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
All the code including the smart contract is open source and the links are provided below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Smart Contract&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/srijanshetty/trinity&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Front End&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/srijanshetty/trinity-web&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bytrinity.xyz&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Mumbai Contract&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mumbai.polygonscan.com/address/0xe87e9c2e04904a42f9d15426fa65d63a1735f52b#code&quot;&gt;Contract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/polygon-devfolio-fellowship/&quot;&gt;Polygon Devfolio Fellowship&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 12, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poor Man's ALB - Apache]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="//srijanshetty.in/technical/poor-mans-alb-apache/" />
  <id>//srijanshetty.in/technical/poor-mans-alb-apache</id>
  <published>2022-09-02T00:41:54+05:30</published>
  <updated>2022-09-02T00:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>//srijanshetty.in</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;One complicated aspect of SEO is hosting your blog on the same domain as the rest of the site. This is arguably very
simple on AWS via ALB which allows sublocation routing, but it became a nightmare when we had to move our resources
awayt from AWS once we had to shutdown our startups and keep the blog churning content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wordpress is a lingua franca for most content online, but the way it handles URLs internally is aggregious. My first
instinct was to host wordpress via nginx, using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;proxy_pass&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SSL termination&lt;/code&gt; at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nginx&lt;/code&gt;. But wordpress decided to
act like a brashful teenager. Finally I caved and hosted wordpress with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apache&lt;/code&gt; on a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt; subdomain here &lt;a href=&quot;https://allround.club/blog&quot;&gt;allround
blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The second part of the problem was running &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;next.js&lt;/code&gt; on the same host on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; path. Apache has &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ProxyPass&lt;/code&gt;, but my
first attempt wasn’t very succesful and after some researching (sic) on the internet, this was the final solution that
worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-apache&quot; data-lang=&quot;apache&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ProxyPass&lt;/span&gt; /blog !
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Alias&lt;/span&gt; /blog /path/to/wordpress

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;Directory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt; /path/to/wordpress&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;FollowSymLinks&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;AllowOverride&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;Limit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;Options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;FileInfo&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;DirectoryIndex&lt;/span&gt; index.php
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Order&lt;/span&gt; allow,deny
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Allow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;Directory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;Directory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt; /path/to/wordpress/wp-content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;FollowSymLinks&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Order&lt;/span&gt; allow,deny
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Allow&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;Directory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ProxyPass&lt;/span&gt; 		/ http://localhost:3001/
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ProxyPassReverse&lt;/span&gt; 	/ http://localhost:3001/
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ProxyPreserveHost&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;LogLevel&lt;/span&gt; warn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ProxyPass /blog !&lt;/code&gt; which ensured that we can use apache for sublocation routing. On port 3001, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;next.js&lt;/code&gt;
was running &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;supervisor&lt;/code&gt; (my goto solution for running apps on a box).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in/technical/poor-mans-alb-apache/&quot;&gt;Poor Man's ALB - Apache&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;//srijanshetty.in&quot;&gt;Srijan R. Shetty&lt;/a&gt; on September 02, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
