<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Lost Echoes</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2015-08-08T23:50:38-04:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelogue - Central Park, NY]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-central-park-ny/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-central-park-ny</id>
  <published>2015-08-03T22:46:40-04:00</published>
  <updated>2015-08-03T22:46:40-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s the search of greener pastures,&lt;br /&gt;
The fear of these barren lands,&lt;br /&gt;
The tireless flow of currents,&lt;br /&gt;
The fear of being left ashore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The pursuit of infinity,&lt;br /&gt;
The fear of being average.&lt;br /&gt;
The search of Neverland,&lt;br /&gt;
Lest you remain anchored.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fuels an eclectic passion,&lt;br /&gt;
A desire to transcend,&lt;br /&gt;
To nourish, to create,&lt;br /&gt;
To leave, and to move.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-central-park-ny/&quot;&gt;Travelogue - Central Park, NY&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on August 03, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Wilson - What We Know About Software]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/technical/greg-wilson-what-we-know-about-software/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/technical/greg-wilson-what-we-know-about-software</id>
  <published>2015-06-27T12:45:23-04:00</published>
  <updated>2015-06-27T12:45:23-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;A few key takeaways and fun quotes from the insightful talk by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~gvwilson/&quot;&gt;Greg Wilson&lt;/a&gt; titled “What We Actually Know About Software Development, and Why We Believe It’s True”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A programmer should be willing to burn the entire code base down and rebuild if the project
reaches such a stage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code reviews. Just do them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We know nothing about estimating the completion time of software projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conway’s Law: The code structure closely resembles the structure of the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As programmers, we can understand only small patches. (It’s because coding is a very complex task.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engineering is the love-child of Science and Economics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask for citations, back everything with data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing the problem complexity non linearly increases the solution complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Platform independent code provides platform independent performance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coders produce the same number of lines of code disregarding the language they code in.
As a consequence, we should be coding in a language higher up in the abstraction pyramid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We as a society have very low standards of proof.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most OOP metrics perform no better than a simple LOC measurement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of the time of developing a project lies in requirements and design phase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A possible reason while agile works is that we work on smaller parts of the project and hence
this might lead to reduced time in requirements phase. &lt;em&gt;Research Needed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All progress in science isn’t forward, sometimes science has to take a step back, accept that
it faltered and restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would urge all of you to watch the talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/9270320&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/9270320&quot;&gt;Greg Wilson - What We Actually Know About Software Development, and Why We Believe It&amp;#039;s True&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/cusec&quot;&gt;CUSEC&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/technical/greg-wilson-what-we-know-about-software/&quot;&gt;Greg Wilson - What We Know About Software&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on June 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/writeup/computer-science-and-engineering-iit-kanpur/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/writeup/computer-science-and-engineering-iit-kanpur</id>
  <updated>Thu Jun 11 16:01:43 IST 2015T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-06-11T06:23:22-04:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;First of all, I would like to congratulate you and your family for this outstanding feat of clearing JEE ‘15.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Introductions are in order, I am Srijan R Shetty, an alum - it’ll take considerable time to digest that fact - of the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at IIT Kanpur.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Before you embark upon the tedious journey of reading through this entire post, I would urge you to go through Professor Dheeraj Sanghi’s blog “A Guide to JEE Counselling”. Additionally, he’s active on Quora; and most certainly will answer pertinent questions. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are some excellent posts written by my peers at IITK out in the wild and as my computer science education has taught me not to reinvent the wheel, I shall compile the best bits from their articles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why IITK? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Shashwat-Chandra&quot;&gt;Shashwat Chandra&lt;/a&gt; does an excellent job of answering this question:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why IIT Kanpur? The cultural festival of IIT Kanpur, Antaragni, is run virtually entirely by students. The Students’ Gymkhana is a body made of students of all batches. The New SAC (Students’ Activity Centre, a place for people to hang out) was majorly planned by the students of three batches, and the franchises selected for its food court were selected by a panel of students. The degree of freedom given to students at IIT Kanpur is, in my opinion, definitely larger than most other institutes. IIT Kanpur also has the distinct advantage of being in a city that is much lesser developed than places like Mumbai and Delhi. Why is this an advantage? IIT Kanpur has become self-contained, because there is a larger incentive to make everything available on campus. The choices of extra-curricular activities are larger, the food options are cheap and more varied, and all sections of the campus are together, making it a tighter, closer-knit location. Each club has its own advantages. Some clubs improve your speaking skill; others teach you a new art; even others let you hone your intellect in the direction you want. Art, music, literature, dance, electronics, robotics, photography, whatever your interest, there is going to be an outlet. If there isn’t, it is not hard to create an outlet or a club for an interest you feel will benefit you. There are certain to be more people interested in the things you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IITK’s academic curriculum was revised in 2011 and the new curriculum was one of the primary reasons why I joined IITK. The curriculum contains two parts: a departmental core and a compulsory core.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the very first year, all courses are department neutral. You will get to learn Mechanics and Electromagnetic Theory in Physics, Organic, Inorganic and Physical Chemistry in Chemistry, Basic Life Sciences (yes Biology!), Engineering Graphics, Linear Algebra and Calculus in Mathematics and (the dreaded) morning exercises. Having the first year being departmental neutral works out for students who change their branches. (A side note on branch changes, don’t bank on them. Albeit I managed to change my branch from Civil to Computer Science, they are a tricky slope to ascend.) To break the monotony and gain a broader outlook, you will be doing at least five Humanities and Social Sciences Courses in your stay at IITK. (I’ve done courses in Philosophy, Psychology, Art, Human Rights and will be doing one in Economics next fall. While people may disagree, I’ve found these courses liberating - pun intended.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The CSE course curriculum looks as follows: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iitk.ac.in/doaa/DOAA/arc2012templete.pdf&quot;&gt;CSE Course Template&lt;/a&gt;, you can cross reference the course numbers from &lt;a href=&quot;http://cse.iitk.ac.in/pages/Courses.html&quot;&gt;Department of Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Priyank-Jaini&quot;&gt;Priyank Jaini&lt;/a&gt; gave a very good overview of how your curriculum will work: (I did make a few changes so that the data matches with that of CSE)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While pursuing CSE at IITK, you will have the option of taking 6 Open Electives(OE), 4 Engineering Science Options(ESO), 4 Departmental Electives(DE), UGP-I(Undergraduate Project)(optional) and UGP-II &amp;amp; III (Undergraduate Project II which can be substituted with another DE or OE) and UGP-IV(this is to earn extra credits), 5 HSS courses(2 from level-I HSS and 3 from Level-II HSS bracket).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Open Electives as the name suggests are courses you can opt from any department including your own. These are the courses which render flexibility to your programme. But choosing these courses from a discipline which interests you, you can even go for a Minor in that discipline provided you fulfil the criteria set. For example you are interested in Computer Science, you can take OE’s accordingly that make you eligible to obtain a Minor in CSE after 4years with a Major in Maths(Note: From the current status, CSE Dept. of IIT-Kanpur has offered no Minors and hence the example is a purely hypothetical one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Science Options are courses in other Science discipline like Physics and Chemistry. You will have to choose a total of 2 such courses. Departmental Electives are courses you can choose from your own Department template subject to what courses are offered in the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flexibility of IITK’s new academic programme was what made it an obvious choice for me. You can take up minors in departments which interest you, or take up a secondary major in an another department altogether, you are also given the option for dual degrees. Also with a new branch change policy in place, I believe that it will be easier for students to get a branch change.
(The new academic curriculum is finally stabilizing and only a few minors kinks need to be ironed out).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finally I would like to say: IITK has shaped the person that I’ve become today. In IITK, I developed a new found vigour towards learning in general, which is veritably unlike the rote learning I did in school. I believe this is partly because of professors who spend hours preparing for our next lectures and partly because of the students over here who never fail to me amaze me with what they are capable of (both in life and academics). I’ve been showered with opportunities and I’ve met people who I’ll cherish for a lifetime.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Feel free to ask any questions, you could drop a mail at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#115;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#106;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#064;&amp;#105;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#107;&amp;#046;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#046;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&quot;&gt;&amp;#115;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#106;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#064;&amp;#105;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#107;&amp;#046;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#046;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&lt;/a&gt; or you could ping me on facebook, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/srijanrshetty&quot;&gt;Srijan R Shetty | Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hope this will be of some use.&lt;br /&gt;
Live long and prosper&lt;br /&gt;
Shetty.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/writeup/computer-science-and-engineering-iit-kanpur/&quot;&gt;Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kanpur&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on June 11, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time Travelling With Vim]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/technical/time-travelling-with-vim/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/technical/time-travelling-with-vim</id>
  <published>2015-05-30T02:36:18-04:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-30T02:36:18-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I usually work on many projects at a time and as a consequence, I tend to open many files. Having all
of my data backed in a VCS saves me the hassle of losing any committed data, but it’s always possible to
shoot yourself in the foot by messing up the work tree; and this is where the editor of my choice -
the mighty and glorious - vim comes to the rescue. A little know fact - vim is a superhero - and
one of vim’s superpowers is time travel - and not just any time travel - time travel on steroids.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Other folks may call it persistent undo, but there’s no fooling us! But being the humble superhero that vim
is, you need to tell vim to use time travel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First create an undodir for vim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;mkdir -p ~/.vim/undodir&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you need to enable persistent undo by including the following lines in your vimrc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;set &lt;/span&gt;undofile
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;set &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;undodir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;~/.vim/undodir&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now even if you go on an editing rampage, vim will save the day. The next time, I shall introduce you
to vim’s other superpower - the ability to use the multi-verse.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/technical/time-travelling-with-vim/&quot;&gt;Time Travelling With Vim&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on May 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Officially an Alumni of IIT Kanpur]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/writeup/officially-an-alumni-of-iit-kanpur/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/writeup/officially-an-alumni-of-iit-kanpur</id>
  <updated>Sat May 30 09:54:14 IST 2015T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-05-30T00:21:19-04:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Alumni Contact Program, IIT Kanpur asked me to write this post which was featured
on their facebook page on May 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Kanpur16 #3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Newest Alumni/Alumnae Of IIT Kanpur&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Srijan R Shetty (IITK/B.Tech./CSE/2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
IITK, a microcosm, a melody made of the discordant notes that the fleeting faces of the institute are. And in this cacophony, I found the greatest of treasures - true friendships: seniors, who’ve pushed me out of my comfort zone, and at the helm of life; juniors, who’ve always inspired me to be a better person; and a bunch of crazy whacks who’ve made me realize that life is about the experiences and the people you choose to share them with. Now that I look back, the last four years seem to have lasted a lifetime and if it hadn’t been for these pyscho-whacks - fondly, my wing - who’ve stood by me for no apparent reason, it would have been a very humdrum affair.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps, the most important thing that this institute has taught me is to keep my mind open and to never stop learning.
You meet people from different walks of life, you are faced with different ideologies, ideas traditions and the only way you can appreciate them is with an open mind. Keeping an open mind has also made for some great stories, one in particular relates to getting convinced by a friend to mass bunk a class. Amusingly, in the next class of the same course, the professor maintained a calm demeanour and wasn’t furious at all. We were in for a surprise though, as he soon announced - ‘We completed four chapters in the previous class and the quiz copies for the quiz conducted in the last class has been checked, students are
requested to collect the answer sheets from my office; and the quiz amounts to 25% the course weight.’ The dumbstruck faces all over the class were priceless.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;One last piece of advice, abhor the concept POR (Position Of Responsibility). At the end, you either learn something out of it or there are already enough people with the same POR for it to be of any consequence.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We wish All The Best to Srijan for his future endeavours !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/images/acp-27-05-2015.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/acp-27-05-2015.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/writeup/officially-an-alumni-of-iit-kanpur/&quot;&gt;Officially an Alumni of IIT Kanpur&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on May 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safely Storing GPG Keys]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/technical/safely-storing-gpg-keys/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/technical/safely-storing-gpg-keys</id>
  <updated>Sat May 23 17:24:35 IST 2015T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-05-23T16:59:33-04:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;TL;DR: The next few paragraphs are mindless rants on the chicken-egg safety problem,
any sane person - you I presume - is better off not reading them and directly going to
&lt;a href=&quot;#encryption&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very paranoid when it comes to managing private information like GPG Keys, SSH Keys, and
other sensitive information. (What I call private information is essentially arbitrary, I tend to
use the thumb rule that any kind of key, its meta-data and other information that I wouldn’t want
people reading is private). At the same time, I’m also paranoid of my beloved computer crashing on
me - I know, the thought itself is terrifying but a harsh reality that we need to face. A very nice
quote which is vaguely relevant to this topic by Leslie Lamport:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You know you have a distributed system when the crash of a computer you’ve never
heard of stops you from getting any work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of soul searching – on Google lasting for 10 minutes, I found
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/StackExchange/blackbox&quot;&gt;blackbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a set of git hooks used by the holy
monks of StackExchange to encrypt all data using GPG Keys before adding it version control.
I suddenly felt complete, I was in bliss; I created a git repo, loaded it with all the
private information I wanted and pushed it to git (a private git hosting service and not
GitHub, just for an extra bit of security). I thought that I was done for life, and then
it suddenly struck me, the problem of encryption is essentially a chicken-egg problem. I
still needed a way to secure my GPG Keys and make copies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Detested, I went in for another round of soul searching and now I just AES256 encrypt my GPG Keys,
Base64 encode it (to make them look all nice and clean) and store them in LastPass. (Still stuck in
the chicken-egg problem). The steps have bee illustrated below for the curious.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;encryption&quot;&gt;Encryption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# copy all the relevant information&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cp ~/.gnupg/pubring.gpg gpgkeys/
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cp ~/.gnupg/secring.gpg gpgkeys/
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cp ~/.gnupg/trustdb.gpg gpgkeys/

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# or, instead of backing up trustdb ..&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;gpg --export-ownertrust &amp;gt; gpgkeys/srijanshetty-ownertrust-gpg.txt

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# tar the folder&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;tar cvzf gpgkeys.tar.gz gpgkeys

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# encrypt and base64 encode&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;openssl aes-256-cbc -in gpgkeys.tar.gz -out gpgkeys.tar.gz.enc -a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;decryption&quot;&gt;Decryption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# decypt and base64 decode&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;openssl aes-256-cbc -d -in gpgkeys.tar.gz.enc -out gpgkeys.tar.gz -a

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# untar&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;tar xvzf gpgkeys.tar.gz.enc

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# copy back to gnupg folder&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cp gpgkeys/*.gpg ~/.gnupg/

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# or, if you exported the ownertrust&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;gpg --import-ownertrust srijanshetty-ownertrust-gpg.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/technical/safely-storing-gpg-keys/&quot;&gt;Safely Storing GPG Keys&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on May 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Photographs]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/philosophy/on-photographs/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/philosophy/on-photographs</id>
  <published>2015-05-09T00:10:04-04:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-09T00:10:04-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The popular adage ‘Pics or it didn’t happen’ doesn’t quite resonate with me, and while this does not
mean that I’m against photos - on the contrary, I’m a registered photobomber. It’s just that of late, I’ve
realized that photos deprive us of a very fundamental human desire - desperation. And it is in this
desperation, that moments become immortal memories. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of studies - I say that without citation - have
show that our mind distorts our perception to be more palatable with our understanding of it. And while,
these photos tend to immortalize those memories in their own way, they deprive our minds the opportunity to
recollect and distort. While the merits of such a distortion is debatable - for, some of us would like
our memories unscathed by demise of our minds. I tend to believe that it is in this desperation to recollect
memories that they transcend into something richer. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The hazy recollection refines the things worth remembering
and all other background noise is lost into nothingness. Don’t get me wrong, photographs are vital to cherish
these ephemeral times, but at times, I prefer being vulnerable to the atrocities that time may have on my
memory and trying to fight for the things that I cherish. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And maybe I’m wrong about all of this, but it’s a thought worth a minute.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/philosophy/on-photographs/&quot;&gt;On Photographs&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shell Magic]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/technical/shell-magic/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/technical/shell-magic</id>
  <published>2015-05-04T15:45:32-04:00</published>
  <updated>2015-05-04T15:45:32-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The other day, a friend of mine ran the following command in an attempt to remove wine and it’s dependants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;sudo apt-get purge wine *&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for him, the command worked and did end up removing wine with a whole lot of other system critical
packages. In an attempt to resuscitate his computer, he tried rebooting it and in the moments that ensued, I can
swear I saw the living daylights sucked out of his face. But every cloud has a silver lining and despite the fact
that we could not boot into X, we did have shell access. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately for us, &lt;strong&gt;apt&lt;/strong&gt; maintains a log of all the operations it performs in &lt;em&gt;/var/log/apt/term.log&lt;/em&gt; and while
it would have been easy to just manually make a list of programs that were uninstalled, it wasn’t &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sCZJblyT_XM&quot;&gt;half-assed
&lt;/a&gt; enough. Instead, we summoned the Gods of the shell to aid us in
this conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We began by getting the relevant portion of the log file to another file (while it is possible to work with the
same log file, we didn’t want to go through the hassle of using &lt;strong&gt;sudo&lt;/strong&gt; every time we had to access the log file.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;sudo tail -177 /var/log/apt/term.log &amp;gt; temp.log&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, we cheated a bit by using &lt;strong&gt;177&lt;/strong&gt; and while it could have been programmed easily using &lt;strong&gt;grep&lt;/strong&gt;, we were
more excited about what we had to do next to really worry about making all of this reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Log started: 2015-05-01  10:36:15
Removing cmake
Processing triggers &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; man-db
Log ended: 2015-05-01  10:36:29&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, &lt;strong&gt;apt&lt;/strong&gt; logs all removed programs as *Removing &lt;program_name&gt;*, so a simple **grep** search
would list all the lines containing the removed programs and the second field of these lines would get us
a list of all the programs which were removed by this operation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/program_name&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cat temp.log &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; grep &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;^Removing&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; awk &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;{print \$2}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The carat in &lt;strong&gt;grep&lt;/strong&gt;’s argument signifies that we want all lines starting with the word ‘Removing’. Also,
we use &lt;strong&gt;awk&lt;/strong&gt; to obtain the second field of the lines (an astute reader may suggest alternatives like
&lt;strong&gt;cut&lt;/strong&gt; as well). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now that we had a list of the uninstalled programs, all that is left is feeding this list to &lt;strong&gt;apt&lt;/strong&gt; for
installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cat temp.log &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; grep &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;^Removing&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; awk &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;{print \$2}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; xargs sudo apt-get install -y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And viola! All was back to normal in Linux Land.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/technical/shell-magic/&quot;&gt;Shell Magic&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Programming Bug]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/technical/first-programming-bug/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/technical/first-programming-bug</id>
  <updated>Sat Apr  4 20:44:37 IST 2015T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-04-04T08:53:20-04:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This article has been featured on this blog for the sole purpose of embarrassing the author, who incidentally is also the author of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prima facie, ECMAScript – the most popular language of the world – appears to be an innocuous, straightforward language; but once you start getting serious with it, it is only then that it will reveal its myriad idiosyncrasies. What is truly remarkable is the fact that despite the fact that many seasoned veterans have been confounded by this language, it has now become ubiquitous in the world of computers.
My first encounter with this language left me exasperated. I was fairly competent in C/C++ and in my hubris thought not much of this “petty scripting language”, and surely I was in for a surprise. Having spent a long 20 minutes on a comprehensive three page ECMAScript primer, I proceeded to write a simple program. The program was to subtract two numbers and return the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit too simple for someone who has vanquished behemoths like C, so I increased the repertoire of this function. I recalled that the primer had a section on object literals, which seemed like a great feature to test. I modified the program to add abilities of subtraction and multiplication using an object literal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;calc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;mul&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this ostensibly trivial change, I tried running the program but in vain, for, for every input, the computer adamantly spewed the same output: “undefined”. This was nothing out of the ordinary, and I proceeded with an error correction drill which was ingrained in my brain after all the hours of programming in C.  I checked for syntax errors - none.  Then I tried to narrow down the possibilities of error and commented out various portions of the code — which as you can see was very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;calc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// sub&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// mul&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program still did not budge. Ideally I would have turned to a debugger and tried out various sophisticated debugging techniques (read ‘stare at the program and plead for mercy’); but ECMAScript was an altogether new beast, I was at loss. So, with no solution in sight, I turned to my my final recourse - google. After a few hours of searching and reading thread after thread of solutions, I finally found the error. The correct code was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;calc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And viola, the bug was fixed. Yes, the difference between my original code and the correct code is not evident at first sight, but nevertheless, was significant. The placement of the brace matters in ECMAScript because, of something known as semicolon insertion performed by the ECMAScript engines. A statement like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is translated into&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;undefined&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so my program always produced “undefined” as its result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular vignette taught me humility, and ever since then, I’ve never started writing a computer program in an alien language without spending sufficient time going through the documentation and specification of the language.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/technical/first-programming-bug/&quot;&gt;First Programming Bug&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on April 04, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelogue - Nepal]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-nepal/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-nepal</id>
  <updated>Thu Mar 26 12:06:04 IST 2015T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-03-26T12:06:15-04:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;As fear crippled my thoughts,&lt;br /&gt;
I could see an impending doom.&lt;br /&gt;
Not the valley that lay ahead,&lt;br /&gt;
An irrational fear did consume.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the ledge came to an end,&lt;br /&gt;
My heart swelled with hope,&lt;br /&gt;
Of living a brighter tomorrow,&lt;br /&gt;
Not constrained by this rope.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So, I took the leap of faith,&lt;br /&gt;
To my friends echoing my name.&lt;br /&gt;
And in those few seconds I knew,&lt;br /&gt;
Life would never be the same.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;854&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/niShO0BIA6Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-nepal/&quot;&gt;Travelogue - Nepal&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on March 26, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux: Pause and Resume Processes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/hacks/linux-pause-and-resume-processes/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/hacks/linux-pause-and-resume-processes</id>
  <published>2015-03-12T17:29:33-04:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-12T17:29:33-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The last few days have been pretty hectic with two major assignment deadlines. And like every wild goose hunt fuelled by caffeine, they’ve enriched my repertoire.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;R Tree&lt;/strong&gt; assignment for &lt;em&gt;CS618: Searching and Indexing in Databases&lt;/em&gt; involved the insertion of a million data points which took about &lt;strong&gt;forty minutes&lt;/strong&gt; to run to completion. The program was midway through when I realized that I needed some precious CPU time for my other assignment: &lt;strong&gt;fitting a mixture of Gaussian&lt;/strong&gt; to a data-set for &lt;em&gt;CS771: Machine Learning Tools and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve always maintained the racial superiority of my Dell XPS 15 but I knew better than run both these programs simultaneously. With less than three hours to D-Day, I couldn’t afford terminating the &lt;strong&gt;R Tree&lt;/strong&gt; program; it was then by divine providence that I chanced upon the idea of somehow pausing the &lt;strong&gt;R Tree&lt;/strong&gt; program. And guess what, as it turns out, Linux has just the solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Linux scheduler allows to pause any running program and resume it at a later time; and the way to achieve the same is dead simple. To pause a process, run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;kill&lt;/span&gt; -STOP &amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And at any later stage, one can resume the stopped program by issuing the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;kill&lt;/span&gt; -CONT &amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that I was able to pause the &lt;strong&gt;R Tree&lt;/strong&gt; program and save the universe from destruction (Not really, but I did manage to save my grades from destruction)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/hacks/linux-pause-and-resume-processes/&quot;&gt;Linux: Pause and Resume Processes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on March 12, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vcsh, Mr - Dotfiles Nirvana]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/technical/vcsh-mr-dotfiles-nirvana/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/technical/vcsh-mr-dotfiles-nirvana</id>
  <updated>2014-12-27 07:12:20 -0500T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-12-27T07:12:20-05:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dotfiles&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-dotfiles&quot;&gt;Dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#bootstrapping&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-bootstrapping&quot;&gt;Bootstrapping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#organization&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-organization&quot;&gt;Organization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#walk-through&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-walk-through&quot;&gt;Walk-through&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#adding-a-new-repository&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-adding-a-new-repository&quot;&gt;Adding a new repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#reproduction-of-configuration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-reproduction-of-configuration&quot;&gt;Reproduction of configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#updating-a-repository&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-updating-a-repository&quot;&gt;Updating a repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#gitignore&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-gitignore&quot;&gt;gitignore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#caveats&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-caveats&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dotfiles&quot;&gt;Dotfiles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started on the path of managing my dotfiles, I was naive enough to believe that my scripting abilities would let me conquer the beast that &lt;em&gt;dotfiles&lt;/em&gt; are, and it took me a couple of years to realize my folly. But I’ve decided to mend my ways, to follow the wisdom of the ages - &lt;strong&gt;UNIX way&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bootstrapping&quot;&gt;Bootstrapping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install -y vcsh myrepos
vcsh clone git@github.com:srijanshetty/vcsh-mr.git
mr up&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to get down and dirty? You need to go &lt;a href=&quot;#walk-through&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organization&quot;&gt;Organization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three vital pieces of the puzzle: vcsh, mr and the directory structure of mr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vcsh&lt;/strong&gt;: The ~500 LOC of vcsh bellies it unfathomable power. Like every great UNIX utility, vcsh builds upon another great UNIX utility - &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt;. Git allows for the $GIT_DIR to be separate from the $GIT_WORKING_TREE. What this means is that the ‘.git
‘ directory could be located in another folder and Git would still work fine. vcsh keeps all these ‘.git’ folders in ~/.config/vcsh/repo.d/REPO_NAME.git. And the work trees are maintained in $HOME. So, we can have multiple git directories residing within home and none of them will collide with each other. Awesome isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mr&lt;/strong&gt;: mr allows to manage multiple repositories together. You register repositories with mr (Using &lt;em&gt;mr reg&lt;/em&gt;, D’oh) and then you can execute VCS commands like push, update, checkout on them together. mr supports all popular version controls systems. (I only care about git though).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Directory Structure&lt;/strong&gt;: The author of the vcsh work flow prescribes the following directory structure:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;~/.config/mr/
    ├── available.d
    │   ├── beets.vcsh
    │   ├── git.vcsh
    │   ├── ledger.vcsh
    │   ├── misc.vcsh
    │   ├── mr.vcsh
    │   ├── template.vcsh
    │   ├── tmux.vcsh
    │   ├── vim.vcsh
    │   ├── xmonad.vcsh
    │   └── zsh.vcsh
    └── config.d
        ├── beets.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/beets.vcsh
        ├── git.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/git.vcsh
        ├── ledger.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/ledger.vcsh
        ├── misc.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/misc.vcsh
        ├── mr.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/mr.vcsh
        ├── tmux.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/tmux.vcsh
        ├── vim.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/vim.vcsh
        └── zsh.vcsh -&amp;gt; ../available.d/zsh.vcsh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some salient points about this directory structure are:
- &lt;strong&gt;available.d&lt;/strong&gt; serves as a store for different available configurations.
- active configurations are symlinked in &lt;strong&gt;config.d&lt;/strong&gt;.
- mr acts only on the configurations listed in &lt;strong&gt;config.d&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s wonderful about these three tools is that they were written by the same author and work together seamlessly!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintaining symlinks seemed too much of a chore for me; and so I did what any respectable programmer would do - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/srijanshetty/custom/blob/master/functions/myrepos.zsh&quot;&gt;automate it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;walk-through&quot;&gt;Walk-through&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me three tries - with the last one taking over a day - in a span of over 4 months to get this straight. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.martin-burger.net/blog/unix-shell/manage-dotfiles-quickly-and-effortlessly/&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt;) guide did wonders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caveat: A lot of this section is derivative of the about mentioned article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adding-a-new-repository&quot;&gt;Adding a new repository&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to manage a new tool and its dotfiles with vcsh and myrepos, follow the steps given below using ack as example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a new remote repository for the tool you want to manage with vcsh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh init ack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The URL to clone that repository might look like: &lt;em&gt;git@github.com/vcsh-ack.git&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add new myrepos config file &lt;em&gt;~/.config/mr/available.d/ack.vcsh&lt;/em&gt;, which might look as follows:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ini&quot; data-lang=&quot;ini&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;[$HOME/.config/vcsh/repo.d/ack.git]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;checkout&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;vcsh clone git@github.com:srijanshetty/vcsh-ack.git ack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a symbolic link to tell mr to include this repository:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/.config/mr/config.d/
ln -s ../available.d/ack.vcsh .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit and push your changes in your local myrepos repository:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh mr add ~/.config/mr
vcsh mr commit -m &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;[ack] add vcsh repository&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
vcsh mr push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the tool’s dotfiles by to vcsh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh ack add .ackrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create, customize, and add the tool-specific excludesfile. (More info about it over &lt;a href=&quot;#gitignore&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh write-gitignore ack
vcsh ack add -f .gitignore.d/ack
vcsh write-gitignore ack
vcsh ack add .gitignore.d/ack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit and push your changes in your local ack repository:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh ack commit -m &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;[Initial Commit] add initial ackrc file&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
vcsh ack push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the initial configuration is quite complicated. But the effort is well worth what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reproduction-of-configuration&quot;&gt;Reproduction of configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install -y vcsh myrepos
vcsh clone git@github.com:srijanshetty/vcsh-mr.git
mr up&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bam! It’s done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;updating-a-repository&quot;&gt;Updating a repository&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work-flow for adding new files/updating files is simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After updating the files or adding new files, run:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh &amp;lt;REPO_NAME&amp;gt; add &amp;lt;FILE_NAME&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then commit the changes and push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh &amp;lt;REPO_NAME&amp;gt; commit -m &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Yowza!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
vcsh &amp;lt;REPO_NAME&amp;gt; push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, vcsh supports all common VCS commands. An easier work-flow is to enter a &lt;em&gt;vcsh chroot&lt;/em&gt;, demonstrated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;vcsh enter REPO_NAME
ga &amp;lt;FILE_NAME&amp;gt;
gcm &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Yowza!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git push
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does this enable the git prompt, but also you can use those aliases that you set. Could this get any better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gitignore&quot;&gt;gitignore&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you tried entering the &lt;em&gt;vcsh chroot&lt;/em&gt; that I just talked about and you use a git prompt (you do use it don’t you), then you’re in for a treat - your terminal may have frozen for a good amount of time; and if you’re like me you would have given up on this vcsh business already. But fret not, such behaviour is expected. Git prompts make use of ls-files and with over 25,000 files in my $HOME, this king of tardiness is expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get around this problem, we need to define a &lt;em&gt;gitignore/excludesfile&lt;/em&gt;. And through &lt;em&gt;vcsh write-gitignore&lt;/em&gt;, vcsh provides us the means to do so. The generated excludesfile is a white-list, for the ack example above, the final generated .gitignore.d/ack file is as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;*
!.ackrc
!.gitignore.d/
!.gitignore.d/ack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first line ignores all files in $HOME and then starts including the files we’re tracking one by one. While this is well and good for normal use-cases, it does cause you to forget adding new files. For example, the generated excludesfile for mr is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;*
!.config
!.config/mr
!.config/mr/available.d
!.config/mr/available.d/mr.vcsh
!.config/mr/available.d/git.vcsh
!.config/mr/config.d
!.config/mr/config.d/mr.vcsh
!.config/mr/config.d/git.vcsh
!.gitignore.d/
!.gitignore.d/mr
!.mrconfig&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see the problem? Okay let me tell you, any new file in &lt;em&gt;available.d/ or config.d/&lt;/em&gt; is ignored by default. So, I’d advise using the following &lt;em&gt;.gitignore.d/mr&lt;/em&gt; file which tracks files by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;*
!.config
!.config/mr
!.config/mr/available.d
!.config/mr/available.d/*
!.config/mr/config.d
!.config/mr/config.d/*
!.gitignore.d
!.gitignore.d/mr
!.mrconfig&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final note on the four sub steps required in Step 9 of [Adding a new repository].
1. Generate a gitignore file.
2. Force add the gitignore file to index, which is ignored up till now.
3. Regenerate the gitignore file (this time it will include the gitignore file itself).
4. Add the now modified gitignore file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caveats&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;The lack a git prompt in my terminal for vcsh enabled repos is unnerving. I still need to soak it all in and find a system to track pending changes. &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All repositories need to share a common README file. Again, I need to find a way around this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;I don&#39;t like the manual symlinking required in .config.d/. It would be much easier to have helper functions like Apache provides for it&#39;s web server.&lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vcsh version 1.2 onwards solves 1 using a &lt;strong&gt;vcsh status&lt;/strong&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/srijanshetty/custom/blob/master/functions/myrepos.zsh&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; script creates wrappers for automating most of this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/technical/vcsh-mr-dotfiles-nirvana/&quot;&gt;Vcsh, Mr - Dotfiles Nirvana&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on December 27, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelogue - Indore]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-indore/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-indore</id>
  <updated>Sat Dec 20 02:09:24 IST 2014T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-12-19T11:34:16-05:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The night of 17th December 2014 is something that I’ll never forget. I’m not sure whether it was the potent alcohol or the nature of our friendship, but the three and half years since our last meeting seemed inconsequential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the night grew colder, emotions flowed, vignettes were shared, achievements were laughed upon and the flame of our friendship burned stronger. It’s funny how much each one of us had changed individually, how far we had left behind our innocent fourteen year old selves, and yet how little we had changed as a group. Mannerisms and appearances didn’t matter then and they didn’t matter now; and yet we spend an eternity in getting them just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe friendship transcends space and time. We parted ways six years ago, in pursuit of different goals, in different cities and yet those memories remain as vivid as yesterday. Maybe it has something to do with the nature of childhood friendships and the pivotal role they play in one’s life. Or maybe it’s just these awesome friends. Whatever may be the reason, I cannot forget the night of 17th December 2014, the promises we made, the stories we shared, the memories we created and most importantly the people I was with, will remain forever etched in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;/images/indore-17-12-2014.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/indore-17-12-2014.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/indore-17-12-2014.jpg&quot; title=&quot;School Friends&quot;&gt;Such nights are to be cherished and such friends rejoiced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such nights are to be cherished and such friends rejoiced. So, cheers to many such nights together.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-indore/&quot;&gt;Travelogue - Indore&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on December 19, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelogue - MT]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/poems/travelogue-mt/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/poems/travelogue-mt</id>
  <updated>2015-02-14 12:36:57 -0500T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-11-16T10:10:24-05:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Wisps of smoke, and a floor cold,&lt;br /&gt;
A broken pavement, centuries old.&lt;br /&gt;
The refuge of wanderers left astray,&lt;br /&gt;
Seeped in our culture - dying today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As the sun kissed the horizon, men poured in,&lt;br /&gt;
Masters once of a habit that pulled them in,&lt;br /&gt;
A curt nod, pleasantries were exchanged,&lt;br /&gt;
All the same, the homeless and estranged.&lt;br /&gt;
Lives intertwined, tales shared,&lt;br /&gt;
Love, grudges - nothing spared.&lt;br /&gt;
Faces of men old and new,&lt;br /&gt;
Friends, who I hardly knew.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And as words became muffled,&lt;br /&gt;
And the light in my hands lost,&lt;br /&gt;
We rose to leave, only to return.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/poems/travelogue-mt/&quot;&gt;Travelogue - MT&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on November 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aham Bhokalam]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/writeup/aham-bhokalam/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/writeup/aham-bhokalam</id>
  <published>2014-07-29T22:56:29-04:00</published>
  <updated>2014-07-29T22:56:29-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Superheroes, Medieval Fantasy, The Mafia - Antaragni has ceaselessly captured my imagination year after year. But despite the fact that I swooned over these themes, I would be fibbing if I claimed that any of themes resonated with what Antaragni could be and what I wanted Antaragni to be. The only theme that could descry what I’m talking about is Antaragni ‘09’s theme - ‘I am the change’. After reaching a certain point, an organization of the likes of Antaragni stops being just another student-run festival and becomes a vehicle of change. Legends like Vishal Dadlani, Raghu Dixit, Rahul Ram bear testimony to Antaragni’s legacy and it’s ability to infuse change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Antaragni stands today for the aspirations of thousands of students who after months of practice compete against the best in the country.Our vision for the festival was very clear, we wanted a theme that the students could identify with, a theme which was steeped in our rich culture and could portray the ambitions of the students who compete here. Choosing a theme which could be a mouthpiece of this sentiment was an uphill task. And after what seemed like an eternity, we came across this gem of a theme which we rejected out of hand. To be frank, it seems absurd in the beginning, but it  grew on all of us. ‘Aham Bhokalam’. You have to marvel the simplicity of the theme, it’s ability to mean different things to different people, its enigma and its closeness to our culture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, the theme has caused its fair share of cause celebre. I for one believe, that the only way to appreciate it would be to let go of the negative connotations we have associated with the word ‘Bhokal’. ‘Aham Bhokalam’ perfectly portrays the spirit of Antaragni - the unfathomable power of the human will - of unleashing the power within. ‘Aham Bhokalam’ for us is a celebration of our indomitable spirit, of finding new meaning in conventional wisdoms, of creating our own paths, of exploring territories where no woman(or man) has ever gone before, to use that line, of being open to the different choices that people make.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The crux of the theme I shall say, is that we can be what we want to be, with of course a zing of our homeland - Kanpur.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/writeup/aham-bhokalam/&quot;&gt;Aham Bhokalam&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on July 29, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why IIT Kanpur?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/writeup/why-iit-kanpur/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/writeup/why-iit-kanpur</id>
  <updated>Wed May 27 11:38:03 IST 2015T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The appeal of metro cities is alluring yet specious. Truth be told, when you graduate, you won’t remember whether you got that obligatory GPL on your birthday in a posh nightclub or in your dainty room; at the end of the day, it would be the people kicking your ass and their sadistic laughter that’ll haunt you for the rest of your mortal life. But that being said, Kanpur fulfills my checklist of all the must haves for a decent city: major motion pictures being released on time, good restaurants, a disco and a mall. (where you can see a bunch of Carrera S’s hanging around!) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m sure that you’d all be wondering what do we do in our free time if we don’t have recourse to the simple pleasures of a metro city. The answer is quite simple - we don’t have free time. IIT Kanpur is always bustling with activity, be it a live screening of a major matche or a movie screening in our badass Open Air Theater (or OAT in IITK parlance), inter hall competitions, club activities, preparations for college festivals (Antaragni, Techkriti, Udghosh), open mics, karaokes, acoustic nights, musical extravaganzas, dance performances, dramatics events and what not. The campus has a plethora of activities to cater to all kinds of people, from the adrenaline junkie to the lazy couch potato. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If someone were to ask me what truly sets IIT Kanpur apart, my answer would be the freedom that the students are given and the trust that the authorities have in us. Starting from the very basic, there is no concept of an “in-time” in hostels, allowing students to pursue moonshots in different technical clubs or just goof around in the campus (or SAC, which has a food court which stays open until 4 am in the morning). There is no internet ban - which by the by, works seamlessly - and neither is our consumption stinted. The messes and canteens come under the purview of the Hall Executive Committee (comprised of elected student representative, again) of each hostel and they choose who the contract goes to (private messes FTW!). The professors won’t take attendance in classes, albeit this doesn’t give the students the liberty to not attend classes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The college festivals: Antaragni, Techkriti and Udghosh are all planned and executed by the Core Teams (students, again) at the behest of the Students’ Gymkhana - which oversees all student activities. The Students’ Senate is an empowered body which acts as a channel to convey the aspirations of students to the Institute authorities; who in turn ensure that all decisions affecting the student body are taken only after consideration of the our opinions. Even the placements, which requires a professional dialogue between multinational companies like Google, Microsoft, Yahoo, McKinsey, BCG etc is handled impeccably by students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
IIT Kanpur is a thriving microcosm, and this post barely scratches the surface of what makes IIT Kanpur so badass.
(Just so you know we won both the Inter IIT Sports General Championship - students and faculty - and Inter IIT Tech General Championship this year which bears testimony to the fact.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other resources:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iitk.ac.in/futurestudents/&quot;&gt;Future Students · IIT Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Sagar-Massand/Rise/IIT-JEE-Counselling-IIT-Kanpur&quot;&gt;IIT Kanpur - the why?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Sharbatanu-Chatterjee/Posts/Legacy-e-IITK&quot;&gt;Legacy-e-IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Govind-Gopakumar/Posts/Aerospace-Engineering-at-IIT-Kanpur&quot;&gt;Aerospace Engineering at Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/sanjana-gopal/why-i-chose-iitk-and-why-i-would-do-it-again/804793606238013&quot;&gt;Chemistry at Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://srijanshetty.quora.com/Computer-Science-Engineering-at-IIT-Kanpur&quot;&gt;Computer Science at Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/archish-mazumdar/a-helping-hand/702010743192719&quot;&gt;Economics at Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://econ-at-iitk.blogspot.in/&quot;&gt;Economics at IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://anshulr.quora.com/Electrical-Engineering-at-IIT-Kanpur&quot;&gt;Electrical Engineering at Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/priyank-jaini/guide-to-bs-mathematics-and-scientific-commputing-iit-kanpur/532987276750044&quot;&gt;Mathematics and Scientific Computing at Kanpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/writeup/why-iit-kanpur/&quot;&gt;Why IIT Kanpur?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on June 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apathy]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/poems/apathy/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/poems/apathy</id>
  <published>2014-06-02T23:03:24-04:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-02T23:03:24-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was the circumstances that made him callous. He found solace in being alone, and the wounds hurt so much that he stopped hurting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An empty pyre,
Melancholic fumes,
An ebbing fire,
As reality looms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A wailing lad,
Unnerved and broken,
An aegis clad,
No tears bespoken.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
An innocent scarred,
A callous youth,
A conscience charred -
Apathy’s the truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hazy pictures,
A could’ve been,
Chants of scriptures,
For a lost kin.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/poems/apathy/&quot;&gt;Apathy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on June 02, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelogue - Kanyakumari]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-kanyakumari/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-kanyakumari</id>
  <published>2014-05-14T23:03:50-04:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-14T23:03:50-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;And the winds blew,
Cleansing my head of,
Dreams I had construe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
And in the blue sea quaint,
I found no expectations to fulfill,
All purposes seemed faint.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
The rock stood glistening,
Unscathed by time; stoic;
Years of mute listening.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
The blue sky dappled indigo,
Vibrant; Couldn’t care less;
Of the many things I let go.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
These valleys, the sea,
Mocked the futility life,
Of aspirations to be.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
Are we near light?
Or are those goals still,
Looming in sight?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-kanyakumari/&quot;&gt;Travelogue - Kanyakumari&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on May 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[They]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/poems/they/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/poems/they</id>
  <published>2014-04-08T19:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-08T19:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;He was never content, he wanted more,&lt;br /&gt;
Every time they met a new face she wore.&lt;br /&gt;
He was assiduous, he could not waste time,&lt;br /&gt;
Whenever they met, she silently stopped time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
He lived in the moment, he had no regrets,&lt;br /&gt;
With him she didn’t think, there were no bets.&lt;br /&gt;
He was eccentric, he could not decide,&lt;br /&gt;
She was the wind that flew with his mind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
He was ostentatious, he liked the lime light,&lt;br /&gt;
She couldn’t care less, gave it without a fight.&lt;br /&gt;
He was restless, he hated to sleep,&lt;br /&gt;
With her he had no promises to keep.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
She had a past she couldn’t let go,&lt;br /&gt;
His past he hid, no one could know.&lt;br /&gt;
A future she couldn’t stop thinking about,&lt;br /&gt;
A thing he preferred being oblivious about.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
She was oblivious of her beauty,&lt;br /&gt;
And he adored her simplicity,&lt;br /&gt;
She always wanted more of his time,&lt;br /&gt;
He would coerce her with his rhyme.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
She wasn’t your typical mushy lady,&lt;br /&gt;
She took both those imposters in stride,&lt;br /&gt;
He wasn’t your typical uptight man,&lt;br /&gt;
He had more than a false pride.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Everything about them seemed odd,&lt;br /&gt;
And despite all of this, they stand -&lt;br /&gt;
this enigmatic pair,  undiscerning,&lt;br /&gt;
Amidst differences, hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/poems/they/&quot;&gt;They&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on April 08, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelogues - Chapora Fort, Goa]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-chapora-fort-goa/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-chapora-fort-goa</id>
  <published>2014-03-24T23:11:49-04:00</published>
  <updated>2014-03-24T23:11:49-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Srijan R. Shetty</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>srijan.shetty+code@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;The shore was calm, the winds silently blew,&lt;br /&gt;
Memories rushed by, and a grin silently grew.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/br/&amp;gt;
Myriad streams inched ahead relentlessly,&lt;br /&gt;
And random thoughts crossed by aimlessly.&lt;br /&gt;
There were no thoughts in particular,&lt;br /&gt;
The waves splashed around in a blur.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Vignettes of what had once been,&lt;br /&gt;
Pebbles that would later gleam.&lt;br /&gt;
Apprehensions about times yet to come,&lt;br /&gt;
Wafts of water evaporated by the sun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
His mind was lost to the waters iridescent,&lt;br /&gt;
Events had transpired, the air smelt different.&lt;br /&gt;
It was hard to believe how life had turned,&lt;br /&gt;
He was far ahead from the last he burned.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And as a maroon spread in the sky,&lt;br /&gt;
He realised it’s time for good bye,&lt;br /&gt;
He picked his satchel, stole one last glance,&lt;br /&gt;
Savoured a view that had come by chance,&lt;br /&gt;
And then he went in a direction new,&lt;br /&gt;
Never to look back at those waters blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/travelogue/travelogue-chapora-fort-goa/&quot;&gt;Travelogues - Chapora Fort, Goa&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Srijan R. Shetty at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Lost Echoes&lt;/a&gt; on March 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
